Just remember.
One step at a time, like we said.
They arrest us, they read us our rights.
We know what we're gonna say.
We've gone through it
a thousand times, and we're ready.
Just don't say a word without a solicitor.
Right?
And remember,
you're in charge.
Then come the police interviews.
They'll try to confuse you,
but don't let them.
Just tell our story...
simply...
and calmly.
No need to make anything up.
Just tell them the truth.
Uh-- Hello there? Mrs. Edwards.
Oh, hello, it's Susan Edwards.
I understand you're being offered as my, um--
Yes, that's right. My name is Douglas Hylton.
And I'll be coming in to help you tonight,
- Mrs. Edwards.
- Oh, good,
because you've heard, I think,
that my husband and I have got ourselves
into a bit of a pickle.
I know it sounds all rather morbid.
Sus-- Susan? Susan? Sorry, can I just--
So, I feel, for his sake,
everyone should know the truth
- from the outset--
- Uh... Uh--
Susan? This isn't a private call
because I'm not actually your representative yet.
Uh-- That's what I'm coming to do now,
you see, to take your instruction,
and then I can-- Does that make sense?
I see, yes, sorry, silly old me.
Just tell our story, simply...
and calmly.
No need to make anything up.
Just tell them the truth.
Thank you.
- Morning, Susan!
- Oh, you came back, then!
- How was your night?
- Oh, you know.
Yeah, first night's the worst.
Uh... The waiting...
Yeah. And also, the-- just not being with Chris,
even though he's just down the corridor.
- Very peculiar.
- Yeah, that's--
- Still, not for long, though.
- Huh?
- Sorry.
Oh. Thank you.
Um-- Douglas, I was wondering...
You know your advice
about not telling the police anything?
Is that because you don't believe us?
Um-- No. It's just to keep it simple,
uh, so that we don't get tripped up.
Uh-- To be honest, it's not my job
to have an opinion, really.
Uh-- My job is-- is to help you.
So when the police start asking questions,
I just ignore them?
You simply let them know
you prefer not to answer.
Uh... You know, most people like
to go with "No comment."
It's "No comment" to everything.
At-- At least until we know... more.
You've gotta remember,
they've only got until tonight
to convince the CPS
that they have enough evidence
to-- to win a trial or get an extension.
If you and Chris don't give them anything,
you might go free.
I can't promise, but it does happen.
Okay. So, "No comment."
And how do we let Chris know
that that's the new plan?
I... um, we-- we don't.
The police aren't...
mega-keen on suspects sharing tactics.
It's just Chris never said
anything about "No comment."
We agreed that we would just tell our story.
We would never have handed ourselves in
if we thought we had something to hide.
Okay. Um...
Tell you what.
How about we...
write a brief statement?
Just the basics. Um...
Your story in your words, very short,
which I'll read out, and after that--
- "No comment."
- Ah, got it.
Um...
Okay. So, go for it, as simply as you can.
Okay. Um...
The day before my parents' deaths,
I took a National Express coach
from Victoria Coach Station to Mansfield.
It was route number...
450 as it was then. It might have changed.
Uh-- Susan, sorry, could you slow down a bit?
Oh, sorry, sorry!
And we don't need the routes and so on.
- Just the important stuff.
- Oh, okay.
Ey up. How you feeling?
- Fucking wired, mate.
- Yeah? You look nervous.
Nah, I'm not nervous. I'm wired.
There's a difference.
It's like there's a little bit
of shit in my pants,
but I'm also really excited.
Well, all power to you, mate.
It's just, 15 years, long time
to get their story straight.
Just tell our story, simply...
and calmly.
No need to make anything up.
Just tell them the truth.
"On the weekend of my parents' deaths,
in May 1998,
while my husband Christopher
was at our home in London,
I took the National Express coach number 450
from London to Mansfield
and visited my parents at their home--"
Well, that was the route number then.
It might be different now,
the way these things go.
Um... "I--" "I took
the National Express coach
number 450
from London to Mansfield and visited my parents
at their home.
All I'm prepared to say is that, firstly,
I am not responsible for the death of my father,
William Wycherley.
I believe my mother,
Patricia Wycherley, shot him.
I will say that I did, in fact,
shoot and fatally injure my mother,
but only after severe provocation.
I was in a very fragile
state of mind at the time.
I would like to make it absolutely clear
that my husband, Christopher Edwards,
had nothing to do with the deaths of my parents.
He was only made aware of their deaths by me,
one week after the incident."
Signed and dated. As I've said,
it's my handwriting,
but it's my client's words.
Thank you, Mr. Hylton.
Susan, are these your words?
Does that reading accurately reflect
the content of your statement?
No comment.
Okay, Susan. If I go to the end of the statement,
- this your signature?
- No comment.
- It's okay, Susan, you can answer.
- Oh, sorry. Yes.
That's my signature, sorry.
That's all right, Susan.
Your statement's very helpful.
So, tell me. When you say
you went to visit your parents,
what was their address in Mansfield?
Five Braxton Close.
And at that time, you're 39?
- Just about to turn 40?
- Yes.
No comment.
Um-- Again, I must stress to you, Susan,
that although it's completely your decision,
my advice remains that you answer all questions,
- "No comment."
- Um... No comment.
I can see you're confused, Susan.
Your solicitor and I are coming
from different angles.
But I'm just trying to establish
some extremely basic facts.
So, if you want to, you can answer.
Right?
You say Christopher Edwards is your husband.
- When did you marry?
- No comment.
Can I ask why you're smiling?
Well, no comment.
- Whoa.
- So, we've uncovered
some slightly dodgy financial activity,
which I've got Sandra looking into,
and apparently they were friends
with Gérard Depardieu.
Whatever the fuck that has to do with anything.
Oh, hello again.
- You done?
- Yes.
Thank you, I-- I'm sorry.
Breakfast, um, isn't really my thing.
But my-- my compliments to the chef, though,
or whoever it is that prepares
the microwave packages.
'Cause scrambled eggs, they're not easy to do
in bulk, are they? They--
They often go hard, don't they?
You still going with that?
Oh, uh, no. All done.
Thank you.
Yeah, it was great! It wasn't what I excepted.
- Oh really?
- No!
How-- How is it so late?
I've missed the last train!
- Well, get a bus, or I'll help you with a taxi?
- It's already so late!
What's the panic? It's not the end of the world.
Look, well, I know it's silly,
But we-- we have this routine.
We usually have a hot--
a cup of hot chocolate together
at bedtime and talk about the day.
We've done it since
I was little, it's story time.
Only, I didn't tell him or Mom
that I was gonna be late,
so they'll be waiting up wanting to go to bed.
Well, just phone them, then.
But if they're sleeping, I'll wake them up.
Okay. How about this?
If you want, if it's easier
for your parents, I mean,
you can stay at mine tonight. I mean, I'm not--
No, uh, no funny business.
But I've got my mom staying, she's on the sofa.
It's a bit of a long story, but, uh...
Well, anyway,
I'll sleep on the floor. You can have my room.
Oh, I couldn't make you do that.
No, honestly, I'd be happy to.
And then in the morning, I can help you get home.
Oh, Chris.
Just to confirm one more time, Chris,
you are content for this interview to continue
without a solicitor?
- I am content.
I don't need someone who knows nothing about me
telling me when and when not to speak.
Right, you understand you can change your mind
- on that at any time?
- So I've been told, yes.
In fact, people won't stop telling me.
Right, thank you.
I can't say I didn't know.
All right. Mr. Edwards, uh,
before we begin with specific questions,
is there anything you would like to tell us
from the outset, anything about
why you think you're here?
Hm. Yes, I would. Thank you.
Uh-- The following is an account
of the events as I recall them.
On a bank holiday weekend in May 1998,
my wife, Susan Edwards, took a coach from London
to visit her parents,
William and Patricia Wycherley, in Mansfield.
I myself remained at home in London.
Now, I went with my wife to Mansfield
the following weekend and only then learned
of the tragic events that had transpired
the previous weekend,
i.e. the death of her parents.
I wanted to ring the police, of course,
but my wife can be very fragile,
and she convinced me
that nobody would understand the complexity
of what had happened
and why she was not at fault.
That's when we, uh...
when we did what families
traditionally used to do,
still do in many parts of the world, in fact,
which is to inter them,
uh, respectfully in their own home, dwelling...
or domicile, if you will.
I mean, the thing that's really
tortured me all these years,
is had I been with her
on that previous, fateful weekend,
none of this would have happened,
you can be sure of that.
And we wouldn't be sitting here right now,
you gentlemen and I, no.
...before '84, everything's black and white.
All right, one last question.
Shut up!
Do you happen to recall the coach company
you and Susan took up to Mansfield?
National Express. Route 450,
as it was then, it might have changed now,
the way these things go.
All right.
Well, I think we've covered
the crux of it,
so, um, we'll take a break there
and, uh, pick things up later,
- if you don't mind, Mr. Edwards.
- Happy to oblige.
- Happy to oblige
with the same bollocks Wifey's peddling.
Only difference is she's got a solicitor.
Yeah, but they've given us
a confession, haven't they?
Of sorts.
Uh-- Dear Christopher,
it was a big mistake to tell
your stepmother about the--
Shut it, Gérard!
What do you reckon they'd get if we take it, sir?
Not enough.
Financial stuff aside,
whatever fraud
they've committed...
...that's-- Oh, yeah, worth doing again.
It went so well the first fucking time.
That's Susan up
on loss of control manslaughter
for shooting her mom,
assuming that severe provocation
business holds up.
So, what, five years?
Eight at most. And Chris
is only getting a year or two,
- if that.
- For what?
Interfering with the duties of a coroner
or some vanilla crap like that.
Which is not bad
if they've actually committed
double murder.
Maybe not such idiots after all.
That story won't hold up
in court though, will it?
Bullet wounds like that.
It's one shooter, surely,
it's just a question of who.
I reckon we press him on that...
- Sir?
-...and then we can--
I wonder if we could try something.
- Mess with their heads a bit.
- Go on.
Could I handle both interviews, sir?
You've got big bollocks today,
don't you, Lancing?
Great.
This is your statement, Susan,
now labelled as item EL-06.
We're glad to have it,
but it doesn't begin to explain
how your parents wound up dead
and buried in the garden, does it?
Do you have a question for my client?
Dozens. How did you first learn
your mother shot your father, Susan?
- Where were you?
- No comment.
Was it daytime or nighttime?
- What about the gun? Whose was it?
- Had you seen it before?
- No comment.
- What'd you do with it afterwards?
- What'd you do with the bodies?
- No comment.
Did you wrap them in duvets?
Put them under the bed?
No comment.
Did you make a phone call around 2:00 a.m.?
Perhaps to your husband, Christopher?
Is-- Is Chris talking? What about his solicitor?
- “No--" "No comment.”
- You said he wouldn't talk!
Your husband's opted not to
take legal advice, Mrs. Edwards.
- Have you told him it's free?
- He knows it's free.
It's just he's chosen to be cooperative.
He's told my colleagues everything he can, Susan,
which makes me look a bit silly, to be honest.
I'm meant to be smart one,
but it's Bill and Ben in the other room
getting all the juicy stuff
from your very charming husband.
Only, he wasn't there, was he, Susan, that night?
So, we're inclined to think
he might be making it all up.
You do want us to know the truth, don't you?
- My advice remains--
- You said he wouldn't talk!
And how he's doing one thing
and I'm doing another,
and we're not together.
- I'm sorry.
- Um-- I'm sorry, Susan,
it's-- it's quite, um, strange,
honestly, but does Chris
know anything?
No, Chris is a very clever man.
You don't have to worry
about that.
- Perhaps you'd like to take a--
- No, I would not!
Okay, Susan. Can we go back to the beginning?
Yes, of course.
Thank you. Let's break it down
- one step at a time, shall we?
- Big balls.
Uh-- Uh-- Do you want me
to leave you alone for a bit?
Or-- Or I can show you where
to get some fresh air maybe.
Oh, I'm fine, thank you.
Okay.
You're doing really well.
- Am I?
- Yeah. Uh... Definitely.
Just... stay strong.
Try not to take the bait.
Okay.
It's October 31st, 2013.
The time is 13:31.
Interview with Christopher Edwards.
Hello, Mr. Edwards. How are you today?
Never better.
May I ask what happened
to the other two officers?
Something more important than this, apparently.
Very rude if you ask me, but anyway...
And thank you for providing
such a thorough account of the awful events
of May 1998.
It's a very sad story, Mr. Edwards.
It is, yes. I'm very happy to help.
Would you mind if we just review a few things?
Not at all, Detective Constable.
Susan was up with her parents in Mansfield,
you're at home in London,
- in Dagenham.
She rings you up in the middle of the night.
You answer. What does she say?
Nothing, really. She couldn't tell me anything.
She was too upset.
Upset about what?
I need you, Chris.
It's all wrong without you.
Well, she'd had a terrible night.
Her mother was drunk, her father, abusive.
The usual story, I'm sad to say.
I can't wait to get back...
to London.
And the next time you see her, you say,
is the following Tuesday.
After the bank holiday Monday.
- Indeed.
- At Victoria Coach Station.
That's right.
You say she'd not told you anything
about what had happened, but was there anything
that struck you as unusual about her? Her mood?
Yes. She was odd. Quiet.
She said, uh...
What was it? Something like...
It was the most awful weekend, Chris.
Really dreadful. I need a drink.
...which was very unusual.
She almost never drinks.
I remember she asked for a port and brandy.
Port and brandy?
Uh... Yes.
Port and brandy.
For the nerves. Shot of brandy,
shot and a half of port.
Right.
Okay. Port and brandy.
And what did you have to drink?
Um... Well, I didn't want a drink.
I had a cup of tea. Earl Grey.
So, you go up to the house the next weekend,
week after Susan first went up.
She having said nothing that whole week
about having killed her parents.
About her mother killing her father.
About her killing her mother, then.
- She was provoked
- "Provoked." So you say.
- So she says.
- So you both say. Very neat.
Look...
I'm not gonna sit here
and pretend I don't know it's a defense.
Provocation. “Loss of control,”
you call it now, I believe.
Reducing murder to manslaughter.
I see you've done your homework.
It's a good thing
I have. You've just arrested
my wife for murder,
whereas in truth, all she's ever done is suffer.
And I don't think anyone
should go to prison for that, do you?
And as for that night, no, no,
she couldn't have shot them both
because she couldn't have done
anything to hurt her father!
I know her. I know her better than you.
He had too much power over her.
Trouble is,
it looks to us like your in-laws were both shot
from a similar angle,
perhaps by the same person.
Well, I don't know anything about that,
but Susan didn't lie to me.
Okay, so let's get back to you then, Mr. Edwards.
That following Friday,
you both take the coach up to Mansfield.
That is correct.
The Friday, right after I finished work.
And she still hasn't told you?
I'm getting to that.
It wasn't until we arrived at the house.
First, we picked up fish and chips.
We always have fish chips on Fridays.
It's just when I'm tucking in
that Susan starts to act a bit different,
and suddenly, she says something like...
I can't stand it anymore.
They haven't gone away, they're upstairs.
And I'm, of course, you know,
"What are they doing upstairs?
Why don't they come down and say hello?"
Something like that. And then,
I don't remember the exact words
but then she said something like...
- Because they're dead.
And I'm, you know, “What do you mean?”
It's a surreal... disbelief thing.
I lose all interest in my haddock and chips.
And I love haddock and chips, it's my favorite.
A big deal, then.
Well, I've not had a single bite
of haddock since that day.
- Strictly cod.
- Isn't there a smell?
What? Oh, you mean the fish smell?
It was warm that week, we checked.
Yeah, but it was night when we
was eating our fish and chips.
The point is that the bodies
would've been lying there
for days.
Forgive the unpleasant image,
they're your in-laws after all,
but there would've been quite a stench.
Ah.
I, uh-- Yes, well, I know.
That's one of the, uh...
But no, I didn't smell it, but Susan...
Susan said...
or well, later, I think she said
that there had been...
an awful smell, but no, I didn't...
notice it at the time...
myself.
Hard to explain, really,
except, of course, that the house always smelt
overwhelmingly of cigarettes
because of her parents.
- Oh!
Sandra!
Sandra! There you are.
- You're looking for me?
- Oh, yes, sir.
- Sorry.
- Why you apologizing?
I hear you've found
something good.
Just make it quick if you can.
We're in the middle
of these interviews
at the minute.
I spent the morning at the branch in town.
- In the archive room.
- Oh, bank archives.
The glamour never stops, does it?
Yeah, it won't stop.
- Um-- But yeah. So--
- Excuse me.
Uh-- This is a bank statement
for a joint account.
Susan Edwards and Patricia Wycherley.
Right. And if you look over here,
that's the date the account was opened.
This is good, Sandra.
This is very good! Come with me!
Come here! Fuck's sake! I'm not gonna eat you!
First of all, Susan, I'd like to introduce you
to officer Sandra Winters.
- Hello.
- Officer Winters is a member
of our Forensic Financial Department.
Oh, my husband's an accountant.
Can you look at this bank document, please?
Police item CKA-04. Sandra.
Do you recognize that?
That's a bank account statement
showing the joint account
you opened in your name and your mom's.
Can you read the date there,
please? Left-hand side.
- Fifth of May.
- Fifth of May 1998.
So, talk me through it.
You kill your mother, your father's dead as well.
You dispose of the gun. And then first thing
Tuesday morning, after the bank holiday,
9:17 a.m., to be specific,
you transfer a bank account
into you and your mother's names
and withdraw almost half of the funds.
- In cash.
Yes, I-- I...
ca-- can't remember.
You don't need to remember.
It's all there in the document.
Well, yes, uh, as I say, she's been, uh...
Sometimes, she's simply
economical with the truth.
We all are sometimes.
But this. This is difficult.
It's straight after the killings. It's obscene.
It's mercenary. And to be honest with you,
it's a little bit daft.
Well, I think she was obviously very--
It's not confusion, Chris, is it?
Bang, bang, open a bank account?
Well, yes, I...
You said the word, I suppose.
"Mercenary," but...
Is there something you're not telling us, Chris?
Something that could help Susan perhaps?
Because at the moment,
this doesn't paint
a very pretty picture, does it?
It's...
It's a very personal matter.
Personal?
I'll tell you what's personal:
being shot in your own house,
kept under the bed for a week,
and buried in your own back yard for 15 years.
I'd like it on record...
that I don't think it's very fair
what I've just said about Susan...
or rather what you said.
It does her a grave disservice
- to call her a mercenary.
- Why?
Because Susan...
...has always had...
much bigger things to worry about than money.
Right.
Clean sheets on yesterday,
in case you're wondering.
Here's a towel, toothbrush.
Thank you. Are you sure this is all right?
Yeah, of course, yeah, yeah. It's my pleasure.
Is your mom okay?
Yeah, she's fine.
She's, uh...
She's not very well at the moment.
Well, I had a very good time
with you tonight, Susan.
- Me too.
Have a good sleep,
and I'll see you in the morning.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Chris.
You okay for coffee?
Everything's good, Mom. Thanks. Very nice!
- Eggs aren't her strong suit.
It was so nice of her to cook for us.
- Oh!
I'm sorry, I really should go.
- All right.
- Thank you.
All right, then? Both done?
Ooh! Oh, silly me.
- Are you going already, Susan?
- I-- I'm sorry.
I've had a lovely time.
Thank you for your hospitality.
And you're walking her back.
Lovely. Chivalry lives!
Separate rooms and everything. Christopher!
I know I embarrass you,
but I was right about the dating agency,
wasn't I, hmm?
It was my idea.
Might even give it a go myself.
It's very nice to meet you.
You too, Susan. And hopefully...
we'll be seeing each other again.
Okay.
Look, maybe we should just say goodbye here.
Oh.
All right then. Goodbye.
- Bye.
- You've met my mother!
You're embarrassed of me, ain't you?
They're just old-fashioned! Maybe next time!
- Can you let me in?
- Mom?
Dad, please can-- can you let me in?
- I can explain.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Susan.
I know it's been a long day already.
What we need now are your words
on exactly what happened that night.
Chris can't really tell us, because...
uh, according to you both, he wasn't there.
Only you were there.
Now, you say that your mother shot your father.
That's not something
that happens every day, is it?
So the obvious question is, "Why?"
No comment.
Oh.
I thought you were feeling a bit
more comfortable talking to us.
What happened, Susan? Was there an argument
- or disagreement between them?
- No comment.
What did you feel when you saw your father there,
dead on the floor?
Your mother having shot him.
- I felt terrible.
- Terrible.
That's a normal reaction, I think, Susan.
What do you then do with that emotion?
- No comment.
- Do you confront your mother?
- What's she say to you?
These questions have to be answered, Susan.
They don't actually have to be answered, Susan.
- That's not strictly true.
- But this is a horrible event,
isn't it? Two people shot dead.
- Your own parents.
- They're just-- This is what I mean by bait.
But it's not
a full explanation
to say you're simply provoked.
People are gonna provide
their own answers if you don't.
You don't have to say anything, Susan.
No comment.
The bank account you opened
the day after the killings,
Susan,
the pensions you collected,
the sale of the house,
all those debts you had to cover,
that feels like a slightly
better explanation, doesn't it,
to someone who wasn't there?
That this really was all about money.
After all, you'd not seen
your parents for over a year
you say, and then suddenly you pay them a visit?
- And then they die.
- But it wasn't. As I said in my--
We've just been with your husband, Susan.
And do you know what word he used to describe
your behavior? With that bank account?
"Mercenary."
And I'm sorry, but I'm inclined
to think a jury would agree.
He wouldn't say that.
Um-- I think it might be useful
for my client to--
It's on tape, Susan.
Chris told us something else as well, Susan,
that I'd like to ask you about
if you're comfortable with it.
He said that your mother
told you something that night
that you didn't know.
What did your mother tell you that night?
She said, um...
Sorry. Must've been very hard
for him to tell you that.
Can I just-- I'm sorry...
- It's okay, sir. I'll explain.
-...I'd really like to remind--
I know how hard it is.
- But it'll be better for--
- I just said,
I'll explain it.
Even while I was sleeping,
I was aware of shouting,
some sort of row.
But that was nothing unusual
in that household, not at all.
As I told you, I had been drinking a little.
A little more than normal. I don't--
I don't normally drink.
I don't know what time it is, maybe 2:00 a.m.,
and I've been woken by these bangs.
- How many bangs?
- Uh...
I don't know, I was asleep.
Two maybe or-- or just one.
- Definitely not three.
- One or two?
Yes.
And I know immediately that my father's dead.
I don't know how I know, I just know.
And my mom is standing there with a gun,
and there are brass casings on the floor--
Brass casings?
Yeah, uh, spent bullets, I suppose.
And I can tell she's even more drunk
than she was when I want to bed.
And then I say something like,
“What have you done?
You've killed him!”
Something like that, it was a long time ago.
And she says-- I can't give you the exact words,
- but she says something like...
- I had to!
I can't take it anymore, Susan!
- I couldn't look at him.
- Something along those lines.
And then she turns on me, and--
and she's actually waving
the gun at me at this point--
God knows why you care.
After everything you've been through,
grubby, little man.
Horrible, horrible man!
What a disgusting piece of work he was!
And then she throws the gun on the bed
somewhere about here, so I pick it up.
He treated me
as though he was disgusted with me!
- But really--
- Uh-- Sorry, Susan.
- Yes?
- Why'd you pick up the gun?
Uh-- It's just-- Well,
she'd been waving it at me,
and she was drunk, and I suppose I was afraid
that she was gonna pick it up again.
Um-- So, anyway, and then,
she starts saying that thing.
I hated him.
For years, I hated him.
And I hate you too.
Because when I look at you, I know I failed.
I failed you, Susan, and I know that.
I know what he did to you.
I knew it, and I just let it happen.
How do you think I feel about that?
- You knew, Mom? You knew?
- Look, of course I fucking knew!
I'm your mother, aren't I?
And he didn't even want me after that!
He couldn't do it. He couldn't even get it up!
And I've spent the last fifteen years
trying to forget what she said,
so I-- I can't tell you exactly,
but it was something like that.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I am so sorry, Susan.
I'm not a monster. I did my best.
We had some good times together,
though, didn't we?
Even though you were a difficult child--
And all I could think of was
"I want to call my husband."
I even said, "We should call Christopher,
he'd know what to do."
Give up, Susan!
You think he's different, but he's not.
He's not gonna help you!
He's the same as all the others.
He's just using you for the sex!
- No, Mom!
- And then I keep crying
- and she keeps saying these--
- He doesn't love you!
Just accept it
before you get hurt!
Nobody loves you!
- Stop, please stop!
- God knows I tried!
But it's impossible. You're impossible to love!
Stop it, Mom! Stop it!
With your miserable little life.
It would've been better
for all of us if you'd
never ever been fucking born!
I just want to confirm the implications
of what you're saying.
Are you telling us that your father
abused you as a child?
- Yes.
- Sexually?
Yes.
And that was the night you first discovered
- that your mother had known all along?
- Yes.
And you'd never told her?
I was always too afraid
of what my father might do.
I spent my whole life
just trying to wish it away.
Thinking of all those years after school
when she was at work and he...
And Chris, your husband.
Are you sure he wasn't involved in the killings?
I only ask because the bullet holes
on your parents' chests were strikingly similar.
And that bank account, that looks like a plan.
With all this new information today,
some of which is quite important
as my colleague is pointing out,
we will be applying for extra custody time,
- so we can continue.
So we're just trying to get everything
as clear as possible before we progress.
Uh-- I think she's been
pretty clear already, don't you?
Are you sure Chris wasn't involved?
He helped you, didn't he?
He decided to protect you.
- Susan?
Of course he did. He always protects me.
Did he bury the bodies for you?
Yes, he buried the bodies.
He's very practical like that.
He has to be 'cause I'm not,
you see, so he has to be.
Uh-- Susan, if you wanted a break...
We couldn't tell the police.
He understood that, so he took control.
And so...
this was his idea, then? To bury the bodies?
Yes, it was his idea.
He did that for me.
He's the only person in the world...
that's ever made me feel safe.
We'll get it sorted.
He's not allowed to keep you
out of your own house.
Has he always been like that?
It's okay. You don't have to tell me.
No, I...
I do want to tell you.
What is it?
It's just, I've...
I've never told anyone else.
Well...
whatever it is...
it'll be between us.
Just you...
and me.
Susan Edwards had been at her parents' house
when she was woken by a loud bang.
She'd gone into her parents' bedroom.
Her mother had shot her father.
Susan Edwards
claimed an argument
then took place,
during which her mother told her
she knew her father
had abused her as a child.
Now, Susan Edwards admits manslaughter.
- ...manslaughter.
She says killing her mother...
...she was provoked...
- ...provoked...
...into shooting her.
The Edwards
claimed they returned
to the house a week later
and had sat down to eat fish and chips...
...and watched the Eurovision song contest
on television...
...when Susan Edwards suddenly blurted out,
"They're upstairs."
Christopher Edwards said he went upstairs
to find the Wycherleys dead underneath the bed...
...before then dragging the two dead bodies
down the stairs and burying them
here in the garden.
But prosecutors say it was all a lie.
They claim the Edwards jointly planned
to kill the Wycherleys.
Over the years, the Edwards emptied
the elderly couple's bank accounts.
Both she and Christopher Edwards
admit burying the bodies and theft,
but both of them deny murder.