Previously on Yellowjackets...
We're starving.
There's nothing to hunt.
Anyone who wants to come with me is welcome,
but I'm going.
I know I don't have to come with you.
- I need to.
- We're coming, too.
Wait! I'm coming.
What do you want from me?
I want you to tell me the truth.
Travis's bank account was closed
right after he died.
Whoever has that money probably killed Travis.
- What the hell?
- You've been blackmailing us.
You're obviously hiding something from me,
and it's making me feel crazy!
I'm pregnant.
What? With who?
Uh, Randy.
Randy?
What are you doing?
Maybe we could be something.
- Where's Van?!
Oh, my God. She's alive.
She's alive. She's alive!
- She-She's...
- No. No. No. No.
I got you.
- I got you, okay?
Okay, okay. I got you, got you. Got you.
R-Really?
Fire?
"No Return" by Craig Wedren and Anna Waronker
It was cool, nothing fire
Nothing broke
Keep simple
Nothing tired, nothing old
Same as you
Oh, so cute, so revival
So alone
Birthday suit, just a smile
No one home
Same as you
No return, no return
No reason
One, two, three
The devil's after me
Four, five, six
He's always throwing bricks
Seven, eight, nine
He misses every time
- Glory, hallelujah, amen
One, two, three
The devil's after me
Four, five, six
He's always throwing bricks
Seven, eight, nine...
You saved me.
No, Laura Lee. I didn't save you.
He did.
Please.
Just show me a sign.
Do you think they're okay?
They're in God's hands now.
All we can do is have faith.
Hey, honey. I-I thought you were, uh, at Ilana's.
Came home to change.
Okay.
Lucky for you, or Dad might've found this first.
Uh, where was this?
On the floor, near the couch.
You're having him over now?
Can you just keep your voice down?
Oh, I'm sorry, is it time to be discreet?
- Callie--
- Jesus Christ, Mom.
Like, when did you just decide
that he could come inside our house?
Right under Dad's nose?
And please don't explain to me how something
usually kept in a man's pants
ended up on the floor of our living room,
because that's something I don't want to hear.
I'm sorry, Cal.
I really am.
I'm...
This is so shitty, but, like,
let's not act like your dad is
an innocent victim, okay?
I mean, the inventory database? Really? Still?
First you judge me for looking the other way,
and now that I'm doing something about it...
admittedly, not the best thing, not...
just a bad thing, but fucking something, okay,
you're judging me even more.
So, that's it?
You're just gonna keep seeing him?
Mom, you don't even fucking know him.
Honey, it's-it's just not that complicated.
Okay? He's a starving artist.
He's not an axe murderer.
Yeah? Then why can't I find him online?
I mean, like, what is that? "Adam Martin"?
There must be millions.
Where's his website?
His Instagram?
Like, no self-promotion? Nothing?
Uh...
I mean, what are you saying?
I'm saying that everything is on the Internet--
except for your boyfriend.
What if he's conning you, Mom?
Sleeping with a Yellowjacket
so he can turn around and sell the story?
Like, who knows what he fucking wants?
He wants me, Callie. Okay?
I know that that is impossible
for you to understand,
- but I am what he wants.
I'm late for homeroom.
Uh, yes, um, my name is...
Sandra Norberg.
And, uh, yeah, I'm calling from-from the
UConn MFA Studio Arts program.
Yeah. And, um,
I'm-I'm just missing the transcript files
for one of my incoming grad students.
Oh, that would be great.
T-Thank you. Um...
Adam...
Martin.
I think he would've graduated in '07 or '08.
They're-- Okay, I could have
the year wrong. Uh...
There's just no record of-of him at all? Okay.
Thank you so much for your help. Okay. Bye.
- Hey, babe.
Uh...
- What's up?
- Hi.
Uh, oh, my God, what is that?
I got you something.
- What?
- "What?"
From...?
- Yeah.
- Oh, thank...
- thank you.
Um...
Yeah?
If this is an anniversary present,
you are three months and
my entire personality off.
- The reunion is tomorrow.
- Yeah, yes.
You married into homecoming royalty,
so I figured you might want to look the part.
Look, whatever.
To hell with it.
You're gonna be turning heads
there no matter what,
and that is just fine...
...with me.
There are no queens in that deck, you know?
Want to go for a walk?
Bring the rifle? Try to hunt?
Who knows, maybe we'll get lucky.
You go.
You're better at it anyways.
"Fade into Me" by Mazzy Star
I want to hold the hand inside you
Mm.
I want to take the breath that's true
I look to you and I see nothing
Fade
Into you
- Mm.
Strange you never knew
Fade
Into you
Fuck you.
I think it's strange you never knew
Hey.
Is it cool if I...?
Oh. Yeah. Yeah.
So, how'd you convince Misty to go?
Ha. Well...
Believe it or not, I didn't have to.
I did think about it, but, uh...
she beat me to the punch.
Ouch. Dumped by Misty Quigley?
That is-- that's rough, man.
You guys do know that we were never...
Well, I'm pretty sure she's not your type.
Yeah, what's that?
You like guys, right?
What?
- What the hell, Nat?
- No.
- Why would you--
- I'm sorry, I...
I didn't mean to...
I don't know.
It's just, you never look at our boobs.
No, I think it's cool.
You have a... boyfriend?
Yeah, I did.
Paul.
He's a... writer.
He actually wanted me
to move into the city with him.
You know, really be with him, but...
If you lost him, you're afraid
you'd have nothing left.
You don't think that...
that Travis is gay, do you?
We tried to...
you know, and he couldn't.
- He kind of, like, lost...
- Oh.
Right. Yeah.
Well, just so you know, that's not, uh...
It's not exactly unheard-of.
-
- Uh...
guessing that he just got nervous,
- you know, up in his head.
- Mm.
Trust me, Nat, I've seen
the way that kid looks at you.
He's... he's in pretty deep.
I just mean...
don't make too big a deal out of it.
I'm sure he'll be happy to get another chance,
if you want to give him one.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, thanks, Coach.
Listen, Nat.
If, uh...
i-if any of this ever got out...
No, I-I won't tell anyone.
I promise.
I got you.
- Just put...
put one foot in front of the other.
When we get back, we're
gonna need sterile water and...
and thread to stitch up her face.
No. Leave me.
Van, stop it.
It's... not... safe.
Don't say that.
- We're almost there.
Tai. Tai.
L... L...
Let them go.
No.
Go back to the cabin as fast as you can.
We'll be right behind you, okay?
Tai?
Go.
Go!
No. Ah!
Ah.
Caligula, you're being rude.
Your phone's ringing.
Uh, no, it's not.
- Took you long enough.
It's a live feed to my friend's hotel room.
So it is her phone that's ringing.
All right.
Naturally.
Wow. All right.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
Anything?
Nope.
Why aren't you out hunting?
Told Nat to go without me.
Something happen?
Isn't it some philosopher who said, uh,
"Anything that can happen will happen"?
Yeah, I don't know.
I'll, uh, go check my old philosophers handbook.
I just, um...
I think I really fucked things up.
Relationships are bullshit anyway.
Trust me.
Whatever you did, she'll get over it.
Let's face facts, Nat's standards are pretty low.
Cool. Thanks.
I didn't mean you.
And you're basically Brad Pitt
compared to the dirtbags she usually goes for.
Like, ugh, don't get me started
on that Bobby what's-his-face
she was hooking up with
before we left. Like, dude,
you graduated, why are you still
partying with high school girls?
I mean, she missed a week of practice
'cause she was too busy screwing him
in the back of his gross van.
I thought your dad would...
- Bobby who?
- Whatever.
It-it doesn't matter. I'm just, I'm saying...
Bobby who?
Jesus.
Farleigh.
Why, does it matter?
Oh. No.
- Um...
- No. Natalie.
Misty!
- What the fuck? Move.
- No, I will not let you.
- Get...
- Get off my coke, you...
Oh, it burns.
Is that normal?
What are you doing?
I'm trying to protect you.
Oh, my God. You're possessed!
- What the fuck?
- Don't breathe that.
Don't breathe that.
Hey. Can we talk?
Come on. You have to talk to me.
- You can't just keep...
- Bobby Farleigh?
Who told you?
- I can't believe you.
- Travis...
No, you lied to me. You said that you...
That I've only been with two guys. Yeah.
Because I knew that if I told you about it,
then you'd fucking hate me.
That was before I even knew you.
I had no idea about the whole stupid Flex thing.
I made a mistake, okay?
Yeah.
Well, apparently so did I.
What the fuck does that mean?
Hey.
What do you think it means, Nat?
Huh?
Are you seriously gonna ruin this
over something so fucking stupid?
Then I guess it's a good thing
you couldn't get it up.
This would've been a lot harder
if we'd actually fucked.
Was it you?
Right.
Fuck you, Jackie.
It's 100 bpms. Ah, this...
Ah, I lost count. Okay. Let's try again.
You just wasted $300 worth of blow.
A, I will Venmo you.
And B, I couldn't just sit there
and watch you destroy your life.
"Watch"? Watch me?
I-I'll do a 15, 14-- no, 15 count,
- and then I'll multiply by four.
- Uh...
What?
You were spying on me?
Is that what you were doing, you little pervert?
Did you watch me and Kevyn fuck?
No, that was not the point.
Friends watch out for each other.
Not with hidden cameras, they don't.
What the fuck is your problem?
What do you want from me? I knew
- I couldn't trust you.
- You know what?
I just saved you from relapsing.
Who else was gonna do that, Natalie? Huh?
I'm pretty much the best
friend you have right now.
And that's not much of a competition, is it?
You should be thanking me.
I have been working day
and night on Travis's case.
You have no idea
the lengths that I have gone to
to solve that case.
Did you know that Travis's
bank account was emptied out
the day after he died?
Stop it. How do I, how can I trust you?
- You're so full of shit!
- Okay.
You know what? Fine.
Next time, I will just let
you zonk your brains out.
You know that I have never
even tried cocaine before?
Oh, which is what I hope that was, because,
oh, if that was PCP, or bath salts, or-or heroin,
or, fuck, fentanyl,
then I-I will probably be dead in a few minutes.
But... but you know what?
I was willing to take that risk for you.
You expecting someone?
No.
Look who it is.
We got a celebrity in our midst.
Ta-da?
- Hi.
- I was canvassing
in the neighborhood, and I remembered that you...
you used to live around here,
so I-I thought I'd pop by.
Yeah. It's-it's a nice surprise after 20 years.
- Yeah.
Um, I'm sorry.
You're obviously in the middle of dinner. I'm...
Well, yeah, but... No, no, no, no, no.
She can stay. Please. We're...
- we're... Yeah, join us.
- Oh, no, no, no.
I'm sleepwalking again.
How long for?
Couple of weeks, I think.
It's mostly stress, uh, the campaign, and...
...this goddamn blackmail fiasco, and...
Not to mention, Simone and I...
have been having some problems.
How bad is it?
Biscuit's missing.
That's our dog.
I must have freaked him out, and he got out
- the back gate, and...
- Oh.
Sammy loves the shit out of that dog.
Jesus Christ, I'm really fucking this kid up.
- No, Tai...
He's seen me do it, Shauna. He's seen me do it.
He thinks there's some other version of me.
He calls it "the bad one."
I'm afraid to go to sleep.
I spent the night pounding espressos,
just so I can stay in control.
I don't know how bad it's
gonna get this time, but you...
you know how bad it can get.
Yeah.
I just need some fucking sleep.
Hey. Why don't you just stay here tonight?
Callie's not here.
You can sleep in her room.
She's at her friend Ilana's.
I'll stay with you.
Yeah.
Oh, my God. What happened?
Where are Van and Tai?
- Hey, hey.
She...
She told, she told us to leave them.
We had to get help.
Show us which way to go.
- Tai?
- Van?
Van!
Taissa?
Taissa!
- Van!
Are you sure you came this way?
I...
I don't know. I-I can't see anything.
It's so dark.
- It's them.
Hey, it's gonna be okay.
We're gonna get you all fixed up, okay?
- It's gonna be okay.
Okay, so, make sure that you're angled in...
Misty, I think she's got it.
- Okay.
Uh...
- Oh...
Do you ever think about
what our lives would've been like
if, um, you know,
it didn't happen?
Yeah, sometimes.
Well, I was going to go to Brown.
Wow.
I was gonna write amazing papers
on Dorothy Parker and Virginia Woolf.
Thought I would meet, like, a floppy-haired,
sad-eyed poet boy who ran
- the school lit magazine.
Ah.
He was gonna be, like, so smart.
- Oh, God.
- And a little bit
intimidated by me.
We were gonna be, like, full rivals
- until we weren't, you know?
- Yes. Yes.
- That kind of thing.
But then my short stories
would make him fall in love with me anyway.
Yeah.
Then, at some point, I would have to leave him
- brokenhearted, because...
- Oh, no.
- Yeah.
- Aw.
'Cause I'm gonna take my year abroad.
- Oh.
- And that's where
I meet Francois.
I'm sorry, "Francois"?
Yeah, in France.
Yeah.
Oh, please tell me Francois was some sort of
brooding musician.
No. Francois was a mime.
I'm sorry.
- Miming is a serious art form
- in France.
- Okay. Yeah.
Okay.
Well, I was going to go to Howard.
Pre-law, with a double major
in history and philosophy.
And date a bunch of beautiful women,
make first string on the soccer team,
graduate first-- first in my class.
And then I was gonna go to Columbia Law
and land an internship
in one of the biggest firms in the city.
You did do all those things.
Yeah.
But if I'm being honest,
not a single one of those things felt...
real.
No, I don't have his account password.
That's the thing, because...
Well, please, could you just talk to your manager
and, um, and just tell them
that I'm-I'm not his family,
but I'm pretty much...
You're not listening. Can you just help-help me?
Please? No?
Can you fucking help me?!
What the fuck!? Talk to your manager!
You fucking bitch!
Do you believe in love?!
Talk to your fucking manager!
Oh, my God.
You're kidding.
Why, yes, it is.
Hey, Misty.
So this is the deal.
Either you are gonna let me go
right fucking now...
or I'm gonna wring your little boyfriend's neck.
Swear to you, I'll fucking do it.
Fine. Go ahead.
I'll just get another one.
Fine. I will.
Oh, my baby.
My poor little boy.
I didn't mean a word of it.
I didn't mean it.
- You look like hell.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I'm just having one of those days.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
I'm gonna make us something to eat.
I let the fire die down.
I fell asleep.
And I must have been sleepwalking or something,
because when I woke up,
I was in a fucking tree, and...
I'm the reason she went.
And I'm the reason she got hurt.
No...
I don't know what's happening to me, Shauna.
I'm scared to go to sleep.
Then I'll stay awake, okay?
And I won't let you go anywhere.
Shh.
You'll be fine.
I'm having an affair.
What?
Sorry. I don't know why I told you that.
Oh, my God. Don't be sorry. With who?
Oh, shit, wait.
Oh, my God, if you say Randy Walsh,
I am gonna burn this whole fucking town down.
It's just this, um, guy I met.
He's younger.
Oh, my God.
What is he like?
- His name's Adam.
- Mm.
Um, he's an artist.
He's really earnest.
Mm.
In-in a way that, like,
kind of makes you want to punch his face.
But also, sometimes I'm like, "Yeah."
And he just makes me feel something.
Like, the sex is...
it's great, but...
But it's more than that.
Yeah. He makes you feel "it."
Yeah.
Yeah. I know.
Ah, man, I remember that.
Simone doesn't make you feel "it" anymore?
No.
But you know what? It's okay.
What we have is different.
It's stable. It's safe.
And-and... and I like that.
It just, um...
you know, "it"-- whatever that really means--
it-it wasn't any good for me.
It's like if someone made me feel "it"...
...it wasn't gonna be good for anybody, you know?
- Yeah.
I think I do.
My turn.
Ah. Okay.
- Hi.
Oh. These...
So, uh, I was just thinking, and, um,
our interactions have been so kind of, uh...
- how should I put it...
- Hot.
...singularly focused,
that, uh, I realized I don't
know anything about you.
I seem to recall you mocked
all my efforts on that front,
but yeah, sure. What do you want to know?
How about you tell me more about...
your art school days?
You went to Pratt, right?
What was that like?
Oh...
I mean, pretentious, mostly.
What classes did you take?
Who was your favorite professor?
Um...
Okay.
I take it you did some digging,
and you caught me.
Yeah, I didn't go to Pratt,
but I had a girlfriend who went there, Lauren,
and I spent so much time
with her and her friends,
that it kind of felt like I went there.
Um...
Uh, look, I-I just told you
'cause I wanted to impress you.
Did it?
Where did you grow up?
Suburbs of Houston.
High school?
Milby High, class of '04. Go, Buffs.
- Do you have any siblings?
- An older brother.
- Where is he now?
- Ann Arbor, Michigan.
He's a colorectal surgeon.
And he has this book in his house
that's just called Anus.
I'm a ten-year-old,
but it still makes me laugh.
Okay, um, as much as I would love...
...to believe you finally
want to get to know me...
Why don't you tell me what this is really about?
Are you trying to catch me lying about things?
'Cause I swear it was just
the stupid Pratt thing.
It's a crazy thing to lie about.
Well...  I know. I'm sorry.
But the rest of it, Shauna, us,
that's real.
Look, I've got this friend
with a cabin in the woods in the Poconos.
Let's go away for the weekend.
Okay? I'll be an open book.
You can ask me anything.
My first kiss,
my favorite color, my shoe size. I don't know.
Whatever you want. Ask me anything.
How do you propose I explain that?
I don't give a shit.
Just go pack a bag,
and get back here.
I have an announcement.
- Hello!
- Hi! Excuse me!
Thank you.
In light of the expedition ending as it did,
I have decided that I'm going to take
the dead guy's plane and fly south.
I'm going to find us help,
and I'm going to get us out of here.
You're gonna fly?
But y-you don't know how.
I've been studying the flight manual for weeks,
and I checked the gas tank, it's full.
I used to watch my grandpa fly.
He even let me steer a few times.
I know that I can do this.
You can't deny that Van needs
serious medical attention.
She's not the only one.
Shauna, tell them.
I-I really don't...
Tell them.
- What is it?
- Yeah, tell us what?
I'm-I'm pregnant.
You were having sex?
- How far along are you?
- Wait,
did you get knocked up here?
No, I...
It doesn't matter when it happened.
Okay? It just matters that we get them both help.
- Let me just...
- Misty, not right now.
All right. Can everyone just...
Laura Lee,
you can't do this.
No. I-It's not even close to safe.
There is no "safe" anymore, Coach Scott.
It's going to be winter soon.
If I don't do this, we're...
We're all gonna fucking starve.
All right, well,
I'm still the only adult here,
so, no.
I'm not gonna let you do it.
What are you gonna do to stop me, Coach?
Hello, I'm an addict, and my name is Jim.
Hi, Jim.
Welcome to the Chelsea Morning group
of Narcotics Anonymous.
I'd like to start the meeting
with a moment of silence
for the addicts who are still suffering,
and then we'll do the Lord's Prayer.
Oh, Jesus Christ,
- not you.
Come on. I promise
- I won't assault you again.
Um, the last I heard,
you got a promotion at the bank.
What's it to you, Natalie?
I haven't seen you in ten years.
Come on. You were my best sponsor.
I just got out of rehab,
and I wanted to see you.
Why?
I have something
I really need to talk to you about,
and nobody could understand things like you.
Please?
So, you remember that guy...
...that I used to always talk about?
Who was in the plane crash with me?
Trevor?
Travis.
He died.
And the cops
ruled it a suicide,
but I know it wasn't.
And why is that, Natalie?
Because he made me a promise.
And when I was on
the brink...
...he, um...
He made me swear
that I would never do that, and then...
he promised me the same.
And even though my words...
...don't mean much...
I-I know I'm a liar.
He always kept his word.
Always.
I know he didn't kill himself.
For once, I think you're
actually telling me the truth.
I need your help, Suze.
Somebody closed
Travis's bank account
after he died,
and I need to find out who, or
- where that money went...
- I'm sorry. I just,
I can't give out personal account information,
unless you're family. I mean, I could get fired.
I thought you might say that.
Well...
I guess I'm gonna have to call the bank then
and tell them
how you and I
used to feed our habits
by selling your customers'
personal information
to identity thieves.
I think they'd be really interested to know that.
Or they could just be really impressed
by your personal growth.
I wish I'd never fucking met you.
Did you really have to tell everyone?
I mean, how could I not?
Shauna, we have the chance to get you
and the baby out of here.
That's all that matters. It's...
It's not really the time to be keeping secrets.
After the crash,
when we were stuck out there,
I started sleepwalking.
A symptom of the trauma, I guess.
Once we were rescued, it just... just stopped.
But with the stress
of the campaign, and everything that's been
going on, um,
it started happening again.
No, uh...
It's not just happening,
I'm doing it, and it, and it,
and it fucking scares me
because the last time, I...
I... Um...
I think I may have been the one
to let Biscuit out of the house.
- I'm sorry.
It's okay.
- It's okay, baby.
- It's okay. I know, it's okay.
- No.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Baby, baby, baby.
Okay? It's okay.
We will get you help. Whatever you need, okay?
Mm.
And we can, um,
I don't know, find you a sleep study...
What I really need is for you and Sammy
to go stay at your mom's house
for a little while.
What? Why?
I-I just think it would be
better for everybody involved
- if you and...
- No, Taissa, Taissa,
- we're a family.
- Simone...
We're not gonna leave you. We're gonna support...
Simone, Simone, you can't be here!
I don't think I'm making myself clear.
You don't understand. I'm afraid
I'm going to hurt you...
...or Sammy.
Please, baby.
Please. Please.
I am begging you. Please.
Please, just go.
Got any more good ideas?
We look for an asshole covered in glitter.
Wait until you hear the water running,
count to ten,
and then just get out, okay?
Who the fuck are you?
Be safe, okay?
Mm-hmm.
For God's sake, Laura Lee, please.
Don't do this.
Thanks for worrying about me, Coach, but...
this is my purpose.
Just you and me now, Leonard.
Okay. Okay, that's good.
We need to get to 55 before we take off.
Kind of like Back to the Future, remember?
Oh, my gosh.
Leonard, we're flying.
- Oh, my God. She's doing it!
Oh, my God. We're really gonna save them.
What the...
No. No.
Is that smoke?